# **Anatoliy Yastreb**

### **Software Engineer**

Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo, Japan +81 080 8111 6803

anatoliy.yastreb@gmail.com https://ayastreb.me

I'm a web software engineer with vast experience in eCommerce and web development. I've led teams of 3 to 4 developers and have experience setting up team workflow according to industry's best practices.

I'm passionate about complete process of product development - from requirements collection to deployment and impact analysis. I enjoy working with smart people, crafting software which brings value to customers, and continuously improving my skills.

#### Skills

Languages

PHP, JavaScript, Ruby

**Frameworks** 

React, AngularJS, Laravel, Sinatra

WebServices

SOAP, REST, JSON API, oAuth

**Databases & Search** 

MySQL, CouchDB, Redis, ElasticSearch

**Testing** 

PHPUnit, Jest, Jasmine, Selenium

**Continuous Integration** 

Bamboo, Capistrano, TravisCI

### Experience

### **Independent Developer**

Tokyo, Japan, 2017 – Present

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Webpack, CouchDB

- implemented Bandwidth-Hero, a browser extension used by thousands of people
- designed, implemented and launched <u>MoneyTracker.cc</u>, an open-source web app for personal finances tracking

# Senior Software Developer at Luxury Fashion Trade GmbH (fashionette.de)

Düsseldorf, Germany, 2013 - 2017

Technologies: PHP, MySQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

- led successful shop localization in 16 countries
- optimized website performance and availability, reduced downtime by 99%
- played key role in technical design & review processes for new website
- introduced development best practices, such as code review, continuous integration etc

### Software Engineer at Magento, X.commerce, Inc. (an eBay company)

Dnipro, Ukraine, 2011 - 2013

Technologies: PHP, MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, SOAP, REST, oAuth

- implemented prototype of REST API authentication system
- delivered Magento 2 API architecture proposal
- worked on Magento Core API implementation for v1.6 release

#### **Freelance Contractor**

Dnipro, Ukraine, 2007 – 2010

Technologies: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Amazon Web Services

- successfully delivered web app prototype for a social start-up
- worked closely with stakeholders on identifying and shaping new features
- worked with legacy code, implemented new requirements and fixes

## **Projects**

#### **Money Tracker**

#### Maintainer, 2017 - Present

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, PouchDB, CouchDB, Serverless Offline-capable progressive web app for personal finance management.

#### **Bandwidth Hero**

#### Maintainer, 2016 - Present

Technologies: JavaScript, React, Webpack, Node.js

Browser extension which compresses images on the page via proxy server to save data.

#### Jekyll Maps

#### Maintainer, 2016 - Present

Technologies: Ruby

A plugin that allows users to easily create different Google Maps on a Jekyll site.

#### Jekyll

#### Team Captain, 2016 - Present

Technologies: Ruby

As @jekyll/build team captain I help triaging incoming issues, review pull requests and occasionally contribute to bug fixes, refactoring and feature development.

#### **Meal Planner**

#### Founder & Primary Developer, 2015 - Present

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, Ruby, Sinatra, ElasticSearch

Recipe recommendation and nutrition balancing web app.

### Education

#### Coursera

Data Structures and Algorithms, 2016

#### **Udacity**

Tech Entrepreneur Nanodegree, 2015 – 2016

#### National Mining University, Dnepropetrovsk, Ukraine

Bachelor, Management, Economics, 2004 – 2008